Who am I that the Lord of all the earth
Would care to know my name
Would care to feel my hurt
Who am I that the
Bright and Morning Star
Would choose to light the way
For my ever wandering heart
It’s not because of who I am
But because of what You’ve done
It’s not because of what I’ve done
But because of who You are
I am a flower quickly fading
Here today and gone tomorrow
A wave tossed in the ocean
A vapour in the wind
Still You hear me when I am calling
Lord You catch me when I’m falling
And You told me who I am
I am Yours
If you believe you belong to Jesus - let me see you wave your hands.
Who am I
That the eyes that see my sins
Would look on me with love
And watch me rise again
Who am I
That the voice which calms the sea
Would call out through the rain
And calm the storm in me
It’s not because of who I am
But because of what You’ve done
It’s not because of what I’ve done
But because of who You are
I am a flower quickly fading
Here today and gone tomorrow
A wave tossed in the ocean
A vapour in the wind
Still You hear me when I am calling
Lord You catch me when I’m falling
And You told me who I am
I am Yours
I am a flower quickly fading
Here today and gone tomorrow
A wave tossed in the ocean
A vapour in the wind
Still You hear me when I am calling
Lord You catch me when I’m falling
And You told me who I am
I am Yours
I am a flower quickly fading
Here today and gone tomorrow
A wave tossed in the ocean
A vapour in the wind
Still You hear me when I am calling
Lord You catch me when I’m falling
And You told me who I am
I am Yours
You may be seated. Thank you.
Hallelujah.
Viewers all over the world, where can we go from His presence?
We bless His Holy Name.
Hallelujah.
We oftentimes ignore our conscience.
We keep talking about the Holy Spirit. There is nothing bad about that.
We ignore our conscience, our heart,
but oftentimes we call Holy Spirit, which is good...
It is the same conscience the the Holy Spirit uses to guide us.
The Holy Spirit uses our conscience to guide us, to guide our souls.
If we only call the Holy Spirit, there would be nothing for Holy Spirit to use.
Take note of your conscience, your heart.
If your heart is not there for the Holy Spirit, there is nothing the Holy Spirit can do;
He cannot reach you or contact you.
All the time we say; "Holy Spirit, God, Holy Spirit, God, Jesus, Holy Spirit",
but we ignore the fundamentals.
There is no way He could hit you, greet you, or reach you.
That is the very instrument that Holy Spirit uses to guide your soul.
Tell your neighbor: "Don't ignore your conscience".
I cannot hear you.
How do we ignore our conscience?
When you want to pray...
but you don't knot that before you pray, you need to examine yourself.
If you don’t examine yourself and you pray, who are you praying to?
Am I qualified? Am I to pray? What am I doing? Who I am? Where am I coming from?
You should examine yourself first.
Sometimes you even may not pray.
You do the examination.
It might be only an examination you would do - and just end there.
You may wake up in the morning,
look around, and realise that you are on the examination all through.
Yes.
But today we wake up, jump up saying; "Jesus - thank You"...
Yes, good, thank you.
Hallelujah, Hallelujah, bless me, bless me...
Who are you praying to?
Oftentimes, we ignore our conscience, the very instrument used by the Holy Spirit – our heart.
You can be on the examination, and just end the whole thing like that,
without even saying; "God help me",
because you know you are not worthy to even ask for that.
Because you are on the examination - you need to examine yourself.
You are not qualified.
You have to be qualified.
Tell your neighbor: "Don't ignore your conscience".
It is very instrument the Holy Spirit Himself uses to guide us, to hear us.
Yes - the very instrument.
If you want to enter a forest, you have to make a path.
If there is no path, and there are thorns everywhere, you would be looking for any available road,
or path you can follow.
Until you get that, before you enter the forest - that path is what we call heart.
In order to have an effective prayer, there must not be anything between you and God.
This is what we are talking about – holding offences such as anger, bitterness,
pain of the past and so forth.
These are the things that live in our hearts.
This is what we are talking about – conscience, a place where those things live.
This is why many times you pray, you find out that you are talking to yourself.
Don’t ignore your conscience.
The Book of Romans 9:1 says, our conscience is the communication point. That is, the contact point.
It is what?
I cannot hear you.
That is a contact point.
If I cannot contact this place I cannot get to the next place.
That is your heart. If God doesn't contact this place, He cannot touch your soul.
He cannot guide your soul.
He cannot guide you.
Let me put it this way.
If God does not contact you in your heart - He cannot guide you.
He cannot talk to you.
That is your heart.
You can call it your spirit."Heart" means the spirit of man.
But we often ignore it.
We call the Holy Spirit to come, whereas our heart is full of evil.
Offence, anger...
Holy Spirit, come down...
Let's assume that the Holy Spirit comes down. He would be just moving around, because
a place of contact is dead.
Is dead.
This is why you are able to look upon pain, wrong and injustice towards your neighbor unaffected.
You look at your neighbor - let him die, it does not concern me.
You just look upon pain, wrong, injustice towards your neighbour unaffected.
Let him die.
Foolish him.
It is a stupid man.
Or you enjoy seeing your neighbour being in trouble - good.
Yes - it is good for him.
It is just good for him.
You conscience is dead.
If your conscience is alive to God, if you hear that your greatest enemy is in problem,
you will start crying, thinking of how to rescue him.
If your conscience is alive to God and your greatest enemy is in trouble, you will cry and seek a way
to rescue him.
You will be the first person to run to him, to rescue him.
You are able to pay evil for evil because your conscience is dead.
You are able to hold unforgiveness, offence because your conscience is dead.
Don't you know that
as a Christian, your situation could be any foolish thing.
Your situation is used to preserve you.
That is what God normally uses.
It is not a joy or pleasure but a situation is what God often uses to preserve us,
to keep us for a new level, to reform us.
You were able to come to the Synagogue today because of your situation.
Is not because of joy that you come here.
It is one thing or another;
you either come here to give the testimony of the situation God rescued you from, or you are here ...
Is it not a preservation?
Is it not reforming you for better position?
Is it not a blessing?
Our situation is not our enemy but our friend.
Your situation is not your enemy but your friend.
It is your situation that still keeps you going with God.
Many of us here, when faced with release, abundant joy - God would likely lose you.
Strength often comes through situations.
It is not through joy, enjoyment.
Strength often comes through what?
Situation.
Strength.
I can do all things through God, who strengthens me through situation.
Don't ignore your conscience.
Anytime to pray or talk to God, it is time to look inward to see whether you are right or wrong
before you pray.
You look inward to see whether you are right or wrong before you pray.
Don't ignore your conscience.
Your conscience is the very instrument used by the Holy Spirit to guide you.
Tell you neighbor: "Don't ignore your conscience".
There must not be anything between you and God if you want an effective prayer.
Holding offences such as bitterness, anger and so forth are the wall between you and God.
Wall - you build wall.
God is here, you are here. Offence between you.
I do not want you to waste your energy in offering a prayer.
Tell your neighbour: "Don’t waste your energy and effort in prayer; your conscience should not be ignored".
If you ignore your conscience you are wasting your time.
This is why anytime cannot be the best time for a true man of God to pray for you.
God always allots time.
They need a corresponding power to pray.
Corresponding power to pray.
Not any time is the best time to pray.
You cannot just rush and ask; "man of God - pray for me".
This is common today.
You rush to your man of God; "Man of God, please pray for me, in Jesus' name, amen"...
No, any time cannot be the best time.
When Jesus was called to the fest, to demonstrate that He was Messiah, Jesus answered:
"not any time is the best time for me, but any time can be the best for you,
to do whatever you want to do. But me - I need a corresponding grace,
before I can do what you ask me to do".
He said, "No, I am not going".
He said, "My time has not yet come".
If you rush to me asking for a prayer - I have to examine my conscience before praying for you.
That is why you cannot just rush to me, and I will pray.
Because I need to go back to my conscience to see if I am in a position to pray or I need to do some restitution.
Imagine that I just saw somebody in a pool of blood.
Oh my God - I feel it.
My conscience is disturbed now.
And somebody meets me and say, "man of God - pray for me",
when my conscience is not at its best.
It is when our conscience is at its best that we can pray.
When your conscience is at its best.
You know when conscience is at its best...
you don't have anything to think about, to worry about - then you can offer a prayer.
There are certain things you ignore, you don't know.
OK, like you wake up in the morning, after having a serious nightmare.
Maybe somebody abused you or hit you...
You just wake up.
Oh my God, this was a nightmare.
You say, "I rebuke you in the name of Jesus".
Whom are rebuking, when your mind is disturbed?
Whatever you say at that moment it would be filtered through your worries.
What you need to do is to counsel yourself.
You wake up and say, "This was a nightmare. God I cancel it in Jesus' name. Thank you."
You have to make yourself happy.
You have to remember the message you have received in the past,
that when you are weak then you are strong.
You have to remember all this.
You have to recall immediately those messages.
Yes.
When you come to your senses, because when you lose control,
the first thing satan does to make you his disciple is to make you lose control.
When you lose control, you start misbehaving.
If you don’t lose control, satan cannot use you as a disciple or servant.
When you lose control, he takes you as a disciple, and uses you.
If you don't lose control, you reason well.
But when you lose control you cannot reason well.
Then he takes you as a disciple, and he can use you as an errand boy to be sent anywhere he wants you to go.
That is why he uses offence to make you lose control.
Offence is the instrument that makes you lose control.
When offence comes, you lose control.
"Why all this?, I don't know..."
You have lost control.
Then satan comes, and you start doing the work of satan.
With bitterness in your heart, you lose control.
With anger, you lose control.
It is when satan takes us as his disciples.
You have to help.
Those of you who listen to this message; "Don't disturb men of God".
You attend them a lot.
You see man of God sitting down and laughing.
You say, "man of God - pray for me".
Ha.
SCOAN Sunday Service
You meet a man of God on his way and ask, "Man of God - pray for me".
Do you know where the man of God is coming from?
In the same way; you cannot jump into a prayer.
You need to pause to examine your conscience.
Man of God has to do the same.
Our own is too serious.
We need corresponding power to do anything.
"Man of God - pray for me"
We need to examine our hearts before we offer a prayer – effective prayer.
Because if there is something between us and God, we cannot offer a prayer to God.
Take this message home, and I know you will re-address yourself.
You cannot just jump into prayer.
This is why people who want to pray start with worship.
They are doing it for to prepare their heart before going to prayer.
They worship.
They are using that to prepare their hearts before going to prayer.
The Bible says in this world there will be offence; take heart, I have overcome.
Take heart means - don't hold an offence.
There will be an offence - but do not hold it.
Offence will come - let it go, don't hold it.
The word H O L D.
Don't hold it.
When something is passing and I hold it - it can become an instrument to be used,
but when it comes, I'll allow it to go.
This is what the Bible says: in this world there will be an offence.
The offence will come - but do not hold it.
When it comes, allow it to go.
In this world it is not possible for you and me to live without an offence.
Don't hold it.
Don't hold an offence.
It will come.
Let it go.
This is why you have to examine yourself.
Don't ignore your conscience.
Your conscience is the very instrument used to guide you by the Holy Spirit.
Tell your neighbour once again: "don't ignore your conscience".
It is the very instrument used by the Holy Spirit to guide you.
It is like playing a ball. Even the best player cannot start to play without the ball on his feet.
If there is no ball - what are you playing?
In the same way the Holy Spirit cannot get to you without your conscience.
This is why the Bible says: "faith is of man's heart".
Only faith pleases God; faith is of man's heart.
It means it is of man's spirit.
So please, take care of yourself.
Take your pen.
People look upon pain, wrong and injustice towards their neighbours, unaffected.
Tell your neighbour again,
Your neighbour could be your enemy, friend, those who do not share the same faith with you.
The Bible says, love them all.
But because they don't share the same faith with you, when you see them having a problem you ignore them.
You look the other side.
Because they don't share the same faith with you.
You are a Christian, they are not Christians.
Whatever problem they have, you would look the other side.
No.
You have to rescue. Love your neighbour as yourself.
If your spirit, heart or conscience is alive to Christ, you would always be there for your neighbour.
Tell you neighbour,
If your conscience is alive to Christ, you would always be there for your neighbour.
Love your neighbour as yourself.
When you learn that he is in the hospital - you say, my prayer has been answered.
What kind of prayer is that?
He is in the hospital? ...
No.
If it is your enemy...
The Bible says: "I will set a table before you in the presence of your enemy".
If your enemy is not there, the table will be useless.
If your enemy does not live any longer,
and the table is set before you, with the essence of life on it,
it is good for your enemy to see what you've become.
It is good for your enemy to see, that you have become that, what they had thought you wouldn't have.
The thought - you cannot become this or that,
it is better to see for themselves.
That may change them.
You can win their soul.
But all that deadness in the heart; die, kill...
"I will set a table before you in the presence of your enemy. "
There is an essence of life on the table. Those things you need for life; peace, comfort, prosperity.
Us being here today is a good example of what we are talking about.
If we begin to examine the hearts, the consciences of everyone here,
at least forty to fifty percent of you never thought they would come here.
You had a different impression about T.B.Joshua.
You were in opposition to T.B.Joshua in the past.
But today you are alive to see that it is your friend.
It is not your enemy.
If you had died, would you be able to see this?
If I have died then, would I be here today?
"I will set a table before you in the presence of your enemy."
What is the way out?
Ask me for the way out for you.
I want to hear your voice.
What is the way out?
Pray for your enemy.
I repeat. Ask me again.
Prayer from your heart, not from your lips.
From your heart.
Down from your heart.
Ask me again.
What is the way out?
Pray for your enemy.
If you chose the path of praying for your enemy you will have a great relief.
In running to defeat your enemies, you have been to many places, spiritually, physically, morally, financially.
You spent a lot of money.
It provoked sleepless nights, fear, anxiety, pressure.
You put the blame for every nightmare on your enemy.
The pain you go through, is not suffered by your enemy.
It is you who is going through the pain.
Why can't you ignore your enemy and move forward? Pray for them!
You are the one that experience the pain.
If somebody curses you saying, "I curse your leg".
And immediately you start walking like this.
You are going through the pain|, and at the same time you pursue your enemy.
You are going through the pain.
At the same time you are fighting the person who cursed your leg.
There are two battles.
You walk like this.
You follow and curse the man who cursed your leg.
Oh Jesus - I curse him.
When you begin to chase your enemy, you automatically forget your condition
in which you are.
It is not possible to look in two directions at the same time.
When I am looking here, I cannot look there at the same time.
So, If I am going through pain, that that enemy has caused...
If I focus on pursue after my enemy, I would ignore taking care of myself.
This is why your situation is persistent.
The situation you were supposed to go through within one week, lasts one year.
It is because you ignore your condition, and you are pursuing your enemy.
Enemy is something that you should define.
I'm here,
here is my enemy.
If I now ask for progress, and I receive it - I will meet my enemy in that position again; I've left that enemy.
The bigger your success, the bigger your enemy.
Why are you wasting your time when you know it is a normal life.
It is a normal thing, a way of life.
My trials are different from your trials, because of my position.
I will not go through your trial.
You will go through the trials according to your position.
And I will go through my trials according to my position.
It is our position that attracts trials.
What attracts trials?
I cannot hear you.
It is our position that attracts trials.
OK, you are in the university, secondary degree.
They will not send primary school teacher to you.
To come and inspect your job.
It is not possible.
They will send a professor or PhD that can supervise you,
not a primary or secondary school teacher.
In the same way
your position in life attracts persecution and trials.
If your position is big, it will attract big trials.
If your position is small, it will attract small trials.
And you always pray for big position, big blessing.
That big blessing will attract a big trial.
If you do not want trial, you do not want a success in life.
When they speak bad of you,
you know it is a recognition.
They ignore people that do nothing.
If president enters here now, everybody would stand to look.
There would be an attention because of his position.
But if you enter nobody would look at you.
They would say, "please, go back".
They would say, "go back".
The usher would not even let you to enter.
What we are trying to say is that,
what you are going through should not rule your life.
What you are going through does not matter but what matters is whom you are.
It is your situation that has subjected you to what you are today.
Sometimes you can observe people talking to themselves.
You think they have a mental problem. It is not a mental problem.
It is a result of their situation.
You see people walking and laughing.
It is not because of the mental problem.
There is a lot of people on the street that you think are mental - they are not.
It is a result of the overwhelming situation.
When your situation overwhelms you, you lose control.
You become satan's disciple.
Viewers, wherever you are, listen to me.
Don't ignore your conscience.
Your conscience is the very instrument used by the Holy Spirit to guide you, to hear your prayer.
Matthew 5:8 - "Blessed are the pure in heart, for they will see God"
"Blessed are the pure in heart, for they will see God"
Say it again.
I cannot hear you.
"Blessed are the pure in heart, for they will see God"
Think about that.
Blessed are the pure in heart; they shall see God.
Our heart is the very instrument used by the Holy Ghost.
If you ignore it, you ignore God; if you ignore it, you ignore the Holy Spirit.
When it is a time to pray - it a time to examine yourself first.
The time to pray is the time to do what?
You have this. This is a mean of examination.
This is to prepare your way.
This will help your heart to contact the Holy Spirit.
Yes.
It will take you out and take you in.
There is nothing to say to people that hold it, "take more of me".
It is a way to examine your heart.
"Take more of me, give me more You" - it means you are more of yourself.
If you are more of yourself, you are finished - you are losing control.
If we are more of ourselves, we become satan's servants.
"Take more of me, give me more of You"; more of Your faithfulness, Your kindness, Your goodness,
Your holiness, Your humility. Lord Jesus - take more of me, give me more of You.
More of You.
You can know.
With our heart we know Jesus is righteous.
With our heart we know Jesus heals, blesses, saves and delivers.
It is not with our eyes we see.
Some people would say: "I want to see that healing".
Even when you see the healing taking place, you will not receive it.
You would say: "It happened to some people, but it never happened to me. That thing is not working for me."
No.
It is not with our eyes but with our hearts we know Jesus is righteous.
And we are the righteousness of God in Christ Jesus.
Let somebody say;
With our heart we know Jesus is righteous.
We know Jesus heals, saves, blesses, delivers with our hearts.
If you can not see with your heart, you cannot receive from God.
With your heart, you receive healing, blessing, deliverance.
Not seeing it with our eyes.
With our heart, we walk with the Lord, we see the Lord, praise Him and pray.
The Bible says that Christianity lies in the heart.
Let some say; "Christianity lies in the heart".
Again.
"Christianity lies in the heart"
That is it.
But you do not know this.
You say, "T.B. Joshua, I want to see with my eyes."
I want to see.
When I say be healed, they will examine their hand.
How many times he said "be healed"?
"Be healed", "be healed" - oh, two times - let me write it down.
After that he turned right. I will write it.
Look at the way he walks. This is the way he walks - let me write it down.
After that healing he laughed - let me write it.
So now, you will imitate. Be healed! Be healed!
Can you see?
With eyes?
No.
With our heart we know Jesus is righteous.
So, in this case,
if we know in out heart that Jesus is righteous, it means not all people that call the name of Jesus
belong to Jesus.
Because one can say "Jesus" not with the heart.
This is so difficult for ignorants to know who is following Jesus.
It is so difficult for ignorants today to know the true pastor.
It is so difficult for ignorants to know the true Church of God.
And 99% of the people in the world are ignorants.
You want me to repeat?
99% of the people in the world are ignorants when it comes to the things of the Spirit.
I repeat again.
When it comes to the things of the Spirit, heavenly things - 99% of the people of the world are ignorants.
How would they know the true Church?
How would they know the true ministers of God?
How would they know the true worshipper?
How would they know the true person? How would they know who is who?
This is where we find ourselves.
We find ourselves in a very big situation.
What matters most to God is your heart.
Write it down.
Because your heart is the contact point.
You have to guide your heart,
because your heart is the contact point.
Before you call Jesus, take care of your heart first.
How do you take care of your heart? By looking to see if you are holding offences
such as bitterness, anger, hatred, pain of the past and so forth.
If you do, don't be surprised if the Bible is no longer real for you.
It means that the value is no longer there.
When you open the Bible and you fall asleep, you know there is something wrong with you.
You open the Bible, you want to read. You start sleeping.
Don't be surprised if the Bible is no longer a value.
It will become a literature.
If you hold an offence, pain of the past, and you open the Bible, you are reading literature, not the Bible.
If you keep the pain of the past, bitterness, hatred, offence, you are not happy, you are disturbed
and you open the Bible you are reading literature, history, not the Bible.
When you are reading the Bible you are reading the Holy Spirit.
You are looking at yourself and He is looking at you.
The Bible is the mirror.
When you look at the mirror you see yourself.
But the Bible is no longer a mirror to you.
Tell your neighbour,
The Holy Bible is a mirror.
That is M I R R O R.
When you take a mirror, and you look at yourself, look through it, you will see yourself.
How you look like.
When you are reading the Bible, you are looking at yourself.
But usually we hold offences all the time.
When we read the Bible while holding an offence, the Bible is no longer real, it cannot be real.
Let me tell you about the Bible.
Holy men were carried along by the Holy Spirit to write the Word you see in the Bible
They were carried along to write what you are reading.
When you want to read, you must also be carried along, when your heart is free.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons
and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing Lives, Changing Nations, and Changing the World